Where all the other Bonds end… this one begins!
Moonraker is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Lewis Gilbert.
After Drax Industries' Moonraker space shuttle is hijacked, secret agent James Bond is assigned to
investigate, traveling to California to meet the company's owner, the mysterious Hugo Drax.
With the help of scientist Dr.
Holly Goodhead, Bond soon uncovers Drax's nefarious plans for humanity, all the while fending off an
old nemesis, Jaws, and venturing to Venice, Rio, the Amazon...and even outer space.
James Bond, played by Roger Moore.
Dr. Holly Goodhead, played by Lois Chiles.
Hugo Drax, played by Michael Lonsdale.
Jaws, played by Richard Kiel.
Corinne Dufour, played by Corinne Cléry.
M, played by Bernard Lee.
Moonraker is a 1979 spy-fi film, the eleventh in the James Bond series produced by Eon
Productions, and the fourth to star Roger Moore as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
The third and final film in the series to be directed by Lewis Gilbert, it
co-stars Lois Chiles, Michael Lonsdale, Corinne Cléry and Richard Kiel.
In the film, Bond investigates the vanishing of a Space Shuttle orbiter, leading
him to Hugo Drax, the owner of the shuttle's manufacturing firm.
Along with astronaut Dr.
Holly Goodhead, Bond follows the mystery from California to Venice, Rio de Janeiro, the Amazon rainforest, and finally into
outer space to prevent a plot to wipe out the world population and repopulate humanity with a master race.
The story was intended by author Ian Fleming to become a film even before he completed the
novel in 1954; he based it on a screenplay manuscript he had devised earlier.
The film's producers had originally intended to make For Your Eyes Only, but chose Moonraker as a result of the resurgence of the
science fiction genre, following the success of Star Wars, and NASA's concurrent test flights of the Space Shuttle.
Budgetary issues led to the film being shot primarily in France; other
locations included Italy, Brazil, Guatemala and the United States.
The soundstages of Pinewood Studios in England, traditionally used for
the series, were only used by the special effects team.
Moonraker had a high production cost of $34 million, more than twice as much
as The Spy Who Loved Me (1977), and it received mixed reviews.
However, the film's visuals were praised, with Derek Meddings being nominated for the Academy Award for Best Visual Effects, and it eventually
became the highest-grossing film of the series at the time with $210.3 million worldwide, a record that stood until 1995's GoldenEye.
This was Bernard Lee's final outing as M before his death in January 1981.
The next film in the series, For Your Eyes Only, followed in 1981.
The film explores themes of space marine, based on novel or
book, venice, italy, mass murder, rio de janeiro.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.